这里同样是标记为A和B的两个三维坐标系，以及相对姿势
Here again are two, 3-dimensional coordinate frames labeled A and B, and the relative pose
一个ksiB，它是B相对于A的姿势。我们已经介绍了点P和我们
A ksi B which is the pose of B with respect to A. We've introduced the point P and we
可以根据关于坐标系原点的向量来描述
can describe that in terms of a vector with respect to the origin of coordinate frame
A，我们就像在上一次演讲中为二维案例所做的那样
A, and we denote that just as we did for the 2-dimensional case in the last lecture in
这种方式，其中P表示向量，A是表示该向量的参考帧
this fashion where P indicates a vector and A is the reference frame that indicates that
矢量P是相对于坐标系A定义的。
the vector P is defined with respect to the coordinate frame A.
我们也可以相对于坐标系B定义这个点，就像它一样
We can also define this point with respect to the coordinate frame B and just as for
在二维情况下，我们可以将矢量从一个坐标系转换为另一个坐标系
the 2-dimensional case, we can transform a vector from one coordinate frame to another
使用点运算符。
using the dot operator.
因此，我们采用相对姿势AksiB并使用点将其应用于向量Pwith
So, we take the relative pose A ksi B and use the dot to apply it to the vector P with
尊重B，我们可以想到中间的B取消和结果
respect to B and we can think of the B's in the middle here cancelling out and the result
是我们留下P相对于坐标框架A定义。我们可以扩展它
is that we are left with P defined with respect to coordinate frame A. We can extend this
处理。
process.
现在，我们可以使用符号相对于坐标框B定义坐标系C.
Now, we can define coordinate frame C with respect to coordinate frame B using the symbol
BksiC.我们可以组成2个相对变换，B相对于A和C.
B ksi C. And we can compose the 2 relative transformations, B with respect to A and C
关于B，为了获得C相对于A的相对姿势，我们使用
with respect to B in order to obtain the relative pose of C with respect to A and we use the
合成运算符，它是一个圆圈内的加号，正是这意味着什么
composition operator which is a plus sign inside a circle and exactly what that means
这是我们将在本讲座后期讨论的内容，但这是一个被称为作曲的过程
is something we'll get to later in this lecture but it's a process referred to as composing
或复合，我们可以无限期地扩展这个过程。
or compounding and we can extend this process indefinitely.
一旦我们复合了这两个相对姿势，现在我们就拥有相对的框架姿势
And once we've compounded these two relative poses, now we have the relative pose of frame
C相对于A，我们可以针对帧C和C来编写矢量的表达式
C with respect to A, we can write an expression for the vector with respect to frame C and
关于框架A的向量，我们可以无限延长这种方法。
the vector with respect to frame A and we can extend this approach indefinitely.
我们已经介绍了一个姿势代数，只有一些简单的规则，这些是
We've introduced a pose algebra and there were just a few simple rules, and these are
与二维情况完全相同。
exactly the same as for the 2-dimensional case.
ksi的实际实现在2-D情况和3-D情况之间有所不同，但是当我们这样做时
The actual implementation of ksi differs between the 2-D case and the 3-D case but when we
根据抽象符号ksi和抽象运算符来处理它，规则是
deal with it in terms of the abstract symbol ksi and abstract operators, the rules are
完全相同。
absolutely identical.
所以，第一条规则就是构图。
So, the first rule is composition.
可以复合两个相对姿势以获得第三相对姿势。
Two relative poses can be compounded to get a third relative pose.
当我们这样做时，有一些重要的检查。
When we do this, there are some important checks.
这两个内部指数必须相等，它们才能有效抵消。
These two inner indices must be equal and they effectively cancel out.
领先指数相同，尾随指数相同。
The leading indices are the same and the trailing indices are the same.
通常，组合物不是可交换的，因此意味着ksi1与ksi2复合
In general, composition is not commutative so that means ksi 1 compounded with ksi 2
不同于ksi2与ksi1复合。
is different to ksi 2 compounded with ksi 1.
有一个零相对姿势的概念，这意味着姿势没有变化，我们代表
There is a notion of a null relative pose, that means no change in the pose and we represent
由符号O.
that by the symbol O.
所以，如果我有一个ksi的相对姿势，我将它与空姿势复合，结果
So, if I have a relative pose of ksi and I compound it with the null pose, the result
是原始的姿势。
is the original pose.
它没有改变姿势。
It's made no change to the pose.
如果我将姿势视为从A到B的相对运动，然后我从B回到
If I consider a pose as a relative motion from A to B, and then I go back from B to
A，我回到了我开始的地方，我没有移动任何距离。
A, I'm back where I started from, I haven't moved any distance.
这是空姿势0。
That's the null pose 0.
如果我与空姿势的倒数复合，再次，我留下我的原始
And if I compound with the inverse of the null pose, again, I'm left with my original
姿势。
pose.
现在对于矢量，我们可以将相对姿势应用于矢量，有效地变换矢量
Now for vectors, we can apply a relative pose to a vector, effectively transforms a vector
从一个坐标系到另一个坐标系。
from one coordinate frame to another.
在这种特殊情况下，它将矢量从帧Y变换到帧X，并进行检查
In this particular case, it transforms the vector from frame Y to frame X, and to check
如果我们做得对，这些内在的两个指数必须相同，我们可以想到
if we've done this right, these inner two indices must be the same, we can think of
他们有效地取消了。
them as effectively cancelling out.
这两个主要指数必须相同。
And these two leading indices must be the same.
这些是非常简单的检查，我们可以用来确保我们编写表达式
These are very simple checks that we can use to ensure that we've written our expressions
正确地说。
down correctly.
这是一个非常复杂的例子，我有大量的三维坐标
Here's a very complex example where I have a large number of 3-dimensional coordinate
代表一些机器人场景的帧。
frames representing some robotics scenario.
我有一个世界坐标框架。
I’ve got a world coordinate frame.
我有一台固定在世界上的相机。
I've got a camera that's fixed in the world.
我有一个机器人。
I've got a robot.
机器人上安装了一个摄像头，世界上有一个机器人物体
There's a camera attached to the robot and there's an object in the world that the robot
正在看，可能想要接受。
is looking at and might want to pick up.
就像二维情况一样，我们可以通过姿势图表示这一点。
Just as for the 2-dimensional case, we can represent this by a pose-graph.
每个节点，这里的每个蓝色圆圈代表一个特定的坐标框架和边缘
Each node, each blue circle here represents a particular coordinate frame and the edges
图表表示相对姿势。
of the graph represent the relative poses.
从这个姿势图表示，我可以写一个像这样的表达式
From this pose graph representation, I can write an expression something like this and
为了检查它是否正确，我们可以在姿势图中以图形方式查看它。
to check that it's correct, we can look at it graphically in the pose-graph.
表达式的左侧显示为红色和表达式的右侧
The left hand side of the expression is shown in red and the right hand side of the expression
以蓝色显示。
is shown in blue.